ABOUT Journal [EXPLORE](http://explore.fatmap.com/) [FAQs](https://fatmap.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/)

Back [Our Vision](https://about.fatmap.com/our-vision) [Careers](https://about.fatmap.com/careers) [News + Press](https://about.fatmap.com/news-and-press)

Back [Blog](https://about.fatmap.com/journal) [Adventure News](https://about.fatmap.com/journal-digest/tag/Adventure%20News) [Newsletter](https://about.fatmap.com/journal-digest/fatmap-newsletters)

Discover a world of adventure...

**FATMAP PRIVACY POLICY**
=========================

Last updated: January 2023

We at FATMAP want you to understand what information we collect, and how we use and share it. Please read this policy carefully to understand our views and practices regarding the collection, use, sharing, retention, and transfer of your personal data. The data controller responsible for your personal data is Terrascope Limited of Berners House, 47-48 Berners Street, C/O Jag Shaw Baker, London W1T 3NF.

### **1\. NOTIFICATION OF CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY**

The most current version of this Privacy Policy governs our processing of your personal data and we may revise this Privacy Policy as needed. We will update this page whenever we revise this policy. We will also provide you notice of any changes to this policy that we determine to be material. By continuing to use our services after changes are made, you are agreeing to accept the changes.

### **2\. INFORMATION WE COLLECT FROM YOU AND WHAT WE USE IT FOR**

* **Location Information** \- FATMAP uses a high-resolution 3D map to display the terrain around you or anywhere in the world. If you consent to sharing your location with FATMAP, your location may be derived from GPS, WiFi positioning and/or your IP address to use FATMAP for navigation or to enable other location-specific features such as track recording.. Your location information or location history may be used for the reasons listed below:

* **Displaying Your Position on the Map -** We use your location information from your device to display your current position on the map. 
    
* **Route Recording -** If you choose to record your route or outing, a detailed history of your location (in the form of a list of latitude and longitude coordinates) is saved for the duration that you explicitly choose to record. This is saved as a route recording in your FATMAP account and is accessible to you at any time on any device where you are logged in with your FATMAP account.
    
* **Location-relevant Adventure Content Recommendations -** In order to provide you with relevant adventure content, your location may be processed in order to show you adventure content, for example, routes, in areas that are relevant to you.  
    
* **Providing the FATMAP Service -** To help us understand our users and improve our services, we need to understand where people are using FATMAP. This helps us, for example, prioritise where to add more map imagery or adventure route content. To do this, we deidentify your device location and securely store it when you perform certain actions in the app, for example, searching for a location or viewing the map.  

* **Account and Profile Information-** You may provide us with personal information for the purpose of creating and managing your unique user profile on FATMAP.

* **Private Account Information -** Basic information such as your name, email address, username, and password are collected so that we can provide you access to our services and manage your FATMAP account, as well as contact you about your account or relevant FATMAP products. We do not use your contact details for marketing or advertising purposes without your explicit consent. If you do provide your consent for marketing, you may opt out at any time. We never sell, share or transmit your personal data to any other company or organisation except for the purpose of providing our services. 
    
* **Public Account Information -** Some information that you provide may be part of your public FATMAP profile. This information may include your name, photo, a description or bio, and other information that you choose to provide for the purpose of building and maintaining your public profile. This information is visible to all other FATMAP users. You can choose which information you publish on your public profile, and you can remove any content at any time by editing your profile.

* **Payment Information** \- When you make a payment on FATMAP, you may provide payment information such as your payment card or other payment details.  We use Payment Card Industry compliant third-party payment services and we do not store or collect payment information.
    
* **Information That You Provide To Us About Your Adventures And Outings  -** Your usage of the FATMAP product may result in you saving or submitting information about your adventures or outings. This may include waypoints or points of interest that you have saved, routes you have planned or recorded, photos you have attached to your outings or plans, the time and date you recorded an outing, or other information you provide about your adventures and outings. You can always choose which information you save in your FATMAP account. You can access this or remove it at any time. Your plans, routes or other content is never shared with anyone without your consent. You can choose to share any content you have created with anyone you like by using share features within the app.  

* **Information You Provide for the FATMAP Guidebook -** If you choose to submit your adventure content to the FATMAP Guidebook, you understand that this content will become public and you give FATMAP the right to display and use that content for FATMAP Guidebooks. 

* **Early Access (BETA) Program -** If you are part of the Early Access Program, your name and email address are stored for the purpose of distributing new application versions to you.  If you choose to send us feedback on the product as part of the beta program, this feedback will be saved and shared with members of the FATMAP product development team who will use your feedback to help improve the product. We may also use your contact details to contact you directly about your feedback. We don't share the feedback with anyone other than the FATMAP team.
    
* **Usage Analytics and Demographic Information -** We store information about usage of the FATMAP services for the purpose of understanding what features of the app are used frequently and how they are used, as well as improving the FATMAP services. This usage information may include, but is not limited to, what adventure destinations you browse, what guidebook adventures you view, how often you use the product or how often you share content with other people.This also includes technical information about your device including the type of mobile device you use, a unique device identifier (for example your Device's IMEI number, the MAC address of the Device's wireless network interface, mobile network information, your mobile operating system or the type of mobile browser you use). 

* **Cookies** - We use cookies on the FATMAP website to distinguish you from other users of the FATMAP services. We may receive information when you view content on our services, even if you have not created an account or are logged out.  This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you use the FATMAP services. For more information about how we use cookies and how you can manage those preferences please visit our Cookie Policy. Disabling the use of cookies using your web browser may impact the functionality of the FATMAP services.

* **We Do Not Use Your Personal Information for Third Party Advertising -** We do not disclose your personal information to any third parties, including advertising partners or ad networks, for advertising purposes, including advertising partners or ad networks. 

### **3\. DISCLOSURE OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**

We share your personal data with the following individuals and entities:

* **Publicly Available Information** \- Your name and other profile information may be viewable by other FATMAP users and the public.  You may also optionally choose to provide additional information and content, such as routes, that may be viewable by other FATMAP users and the public.
    
* **FATMAP Employees** \- Your personal information may be viewed or processed by FATMAP team members if they have a specific and relevant business reason to do so to maintain the product or provide you with the appropriate service.
    
* **FATMAP Partners -** FATMAP provides offers to tours, guides and equipment. With your consent, we may use information we have collected about you to present you with offers such as tours, guides or equipment.  
    
* **Third Party Business via API or Other Integrations -** We may enable you to share your information and content with third party apps, plugins, or websites that integrate with our services.  You can choose to share your data with integrated services.  Information collected by these third parties is subject to their terms and policies.  FATMAP is not responsible for the terms or policies of third parties.  
    
* **Service Providers -** We may share your information with third parties who provide services to FATMAP such as supporting, improving, providing, promoting and securing the Services, processing payments, or fulfilling orders.  We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this policy.
    
* **Parent Company and its Affiliates** - We may share your information with our parent company, Strava, Inc. and its affiliates for analytics purposes, to provide you a more personalized experience, to process your subscription, for marketing purposes in line with your settings, and to help us operate and improve our services.
    
* **Acquirers of Our Business or Assets -** If we become involved in a business combination, securities offering, bankruptcy, reorganization, dissolution or other similar transaction, we may share or transfer your information in connection with such transaction.
    
* **Legal Requirements -** We may share your information if we are under a duty to do so in order to comply with any legal or regulatory obligation, or a court order or other lawful demand.  We may also share your information if we determine that this is reasonably necessary or appropriate to prevent any person from death or serious bodily injury, to address issues of national security or other issues of public importance, or to protect our operations or our property or other legal rights, including by disclosure to our legal counsel and other consultants and third parties in connection with actual or potential litigation.
    
* **With Your Consent Or At Your Request -** We may ask for your consent to share your information in new ways not described in this policy.  When we do, we will notify you about why we want to share the information or provide you an opt-out for sharing your data for specific purposes like marketing.
    
* **In Aggregate Or Deidentified form** \- We may collect and aggregate information, such as how many people use our services, and share it with our partners and affiliates.  When doing so, we design our information-sharing practices to avoid the use of information that directly identifies any individual person.

### **4\. YOUR RIGHTS**

**Opt Out of Processing of Data for Marketing Purposes** \- You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. You can click 'unsubscribe' at the bottom of any email from us to unsubscribe from our email list. To opt out of all processing of your personal data for marketing purposes, you can contact us at support@fatmap.com.

**Delete Your Account** \- You can request to delete your FATMAP account at any time. If you choose to delete your account, your account and personal data will be removed from FATMAP's servers. This is not reversible. To delete your account and all personal data associated with it, email us at [support@fatmap.com](mailto:support@fatmap.com). 

**Request a Copy of Your Data** - You have the right to request an electronic copy of your data at any time. To request a copy of your data, contact us at support@fatmap.com.

**5\. PROTECTING YOUR DATA**

FATMAP strives to follow all necessary privacy and security protocols with the transmission of information via the internet. We look at the risks that may be presented to the data and rely on things like standard contractual clauses, where applicable to ensure your data rights are protected. However, your choice to transmit information using FATMAP’s services is done at your own risk. The data that we collect from you are stored on secure servers. All data is encrypted in transit and at rest in our servers.

### **6\. INTERNATIONAL DATA TRANSFERS**

In the process of providing the Services, we may transfer information across country borders and jurisdictions.  Data transfers from the European Union, United Kingdom, and Switzerland are transferred using legal mechanisms approved by relevant authorities for international data transfers, such as Standard Contractual Clauses.

### **7\. CONTACT US**

Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed and should be addressed to Terrascope Limited of New Penderel House, 4th Floor, 283-288 High Holborn,

London WC1V 7HP or support@fatmap.com.

Support

Discover

Follow

Connect

© 2023 FATMAP

_All photos shot by_ [_Ben Tibbetts Photography_](https://www.bentibbettsphotography.com/)_,_ [_Dan Patitucci_](https://patitucciphoto.com/) _and_ [_Jon Williams_](https://www.jon-w.com/)
